+45 92 16 55 45 https://www.tanvir.dk/



PROFILE

Solutions-orientated and highly regarded for more than 15 years of progressive experience developing, implementing and supporting complex infrastructures and technical solutions for leaders in the industry. Superior expertise with development methodologies, developer supervision and client relations. Motivational and influential project manager, providing effective leadership in fast-paced, deadline driven environments. Track record of surpassing goals and expectations for quality, schedule and cost while implementing leading-edge IT solutions. Out-of-the-box thinker who thrives in collaborative environments, working across business and technical teams to increase profits and reduce costs through continuous improvements and strategic IT infrastructure planning.

EXPERIENCE

CareCom, Denmark —Sr. Frontend Developer

SEP 2019 - PRESENT

- Currently working in HealthTerm application for a new feature `Mapping` module: based on different code systems both international standards and custom code systems, new mapping module will help users use algorithms easily mappings of different code-systems.
- Discover and implement new technologies that yield competitive advantage for the new module mapping.
- Introduced Cyress (End-to-End Testing) and other front-end tech.
- Communicate technology strategy to Team Lead and other developers.
- Use PO's feedback to inform necessary improvements and adjustments to new feature module Mapping.
- Developed and Designed MVP for the new feature module Mapping which was used to gain real-time user feedback.
- Completed standalone web application KodeKatalog a terminology lookup for rules and guidelines for clinical coding systems in the specialist health service such as (ICD-10, NCSP, NCMP and NCRP)

Tools used: HTML5, JSP, CSS, JavaScript (RactiveJS), tomcat, Java, maven, git(gitLab), MAC, PostgradSQL.

EasyTranslate, Denmark — Sr. Fullstack Developer

MAY 2019 - JUL 2019

EasyTranslate is a company that provides different kinds of translation services for different organizations.

 Worked on building a new scalable application to replace a legacy system. The development includes new API endpoints for administrative dashboard tools, integration with 3rd parties platforms such as MemSource and stripe.

Tools used: HTML5, CSS, PHP, JavaScript (vuejs), Laravel, git(gitHub), MAC, phpStorm, Docker, MySQL, CI, phpUnit.

TF-technologies, Denmark — Sr. Fullstack Developer

NOV 2018 - APR 2019

TF-Technologies, the main focus is to develop and produce high-quality electronic control solutions for road construction machinery.

- Worked on MatManager[™], a web application helps control key

Tanvir Alam

Nordvej 19, 1tv 3000, Helsingor tanvir.alam.shawn@gmail.com

KEY SKILLS

- Python
- PHP
- Iava
- Javascript (ES6)
- MySql
- Redis
- Git
- Laravel
- Lumen
- Flask
- VueIs
- React
- RactiveJS
- Redux
- Vuex
- Elastic Search
- PhpUnit
- Cypress
- Linux (Ubuntu 18/20)
- MAC OS
- Continuous Integration CI
- Docker
- PhpStorm
- IntelliJ
- PyCharm
- Vim
- Sublime 2

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Full Life Cycle Development
- Software Analysis & Design
- Object Oriented TechnologyApplication Development
- Program Management
- E-commerce & Websites
- Process Improvement
- Training
- Technical Solutions
- Project Leadership
- Product owner
- Change Management

PERSONALITY

A passionate altruist, sometimes even to a fault, and unlikely to be afraid to take the slings and arrows while standing up for the great people and great ideas.

+45 92 16 55 45 <u>https://www.tanvir.dk/</u>

parameters of asphalt paving jobs and keep track of your workflow and material use throughout the paving job with real-time measurements.

Tools used: HTML5, CSS, PHP, JavaScript (vuejs), Laravel, git(gitHub), Linux (Ubuntu 18), CI, phpUnit, phpStorm, Docker, MySQL.

Dwarf, Denmark — Sr. Fullstack Developer

AUG 2018 - OCT 2018

Dwarf is a digital agency.

Worked on a project based on real estate business and maintenance.
 Main objective was to create different test cases in phpUnit based on each new feature designed.

Tools used: HTML5, CSS, PHP, JavaScript (vuejs), Laravel, git(gitHub), Linux (Ubuntu 18), CI, phpUnit, phpStorm, Docker, MySQL.

Casalogic, Denmark — Fullstack Developer

DEC 2016 - JUN 2018

Casalogic A / S is one of Denmark's first and leading suppliers of Enterprise Open Source products and support.

 Worked on CUBS is a user-friendly and tailor-made system for consumption billing in the utilities sector. Daily tasks were working on issues such as fixing bugs, new features, data migrations, building API.

Tools used: Laravel 5.3, PHP, MySQL, MONGO DB, JavaScript, Vue.js, git(gitHub), Linux (Ubuntu 18), PhpStorm.

Comadso, Denmark — Fullstack Developer

OCT 2015 - NOV 2016

Comadso A/S provides service to both the local and international $\,$ insurance industry.

 Main responsibilities were the development of new features and maintenance of Comadso.com application as per companies' requirement.

Tools used: Laravel 3, PHP, MySQL, JavaScript, Windows 10, Sublime 2.

Pandisign, Denmark — Fullstack Developer

NOV 2014 - MAR 2015

Pandisign is a digital agency.

- Main objective was to design, develop and implement web portal/web site/Web applications as per customer's requirements.

Tools used: Laravel 4, PHP, MySQL, JavaScript, Windows 10, Sublime 2, WordPress

Freelance, Denmark — Fullstack Developer

MAY 2013 - NOV 2014

After relocating to Denmark I had a fabulous time adopting to Danish culture, the job Market, Language and successfully settling down in Denmark along with my family.

- Worked on 2 different web application projects as Freelance.

Tools used: PHP, MySQL, JavaScript, Windows 10, Sublime 2

OPEX TEXTIL, Bangladesh — Head of IT

FEB 2012 - APR 2013

Opex is one of the largest garment manufacturing conglomerates in Asia and has a complete vertical integrated setup in woven, denim, outwear, knit and

LANGUAGES

English (Native or bilingual)
Danish (Elementary)
Swedish (Elementary)
Bangla (Limited)

HOBBIES

Bicycling, graphic design, Hiking, Fishing, Games, Cooking, Camping, Table Tennis, Painting sweater.

- Contribute in the development of the Information System of OPEX GROUP. Developed and Implemented: Export Monitoring System (EMS) and HR Monitoring and Management System.

Tools used: HTML5, CSS, PHP, MySQL, JavaScript, Windows 10, Sublime 2

ASIAN GLOBAL VENTURE, Bangladesh — Sr. Developer

SEP 2011 - JAN 2012

AGV is a software provider agency which provides full service in online business development, design and concept development, and creative web designing, any kind of software development.

- Worked on designing and developing 1 web application project and a IPhone app using X-codes.

Tools used: HTML5, CSS, PHP, MySQL, JavaScript, Windows 10, X-codes, Sublime 2

OTOBI LTD, Bangladesh — Deputy General Manager IT

JUL 2007 - SEP 2011

OTOBI is one of the top furniture maker companies in Bangladesh.

- Main objective was to contribute to the development of the Information System of OTOBI Ltd.
- Leading the MIS team in and developing and implementing various tools and software's.
- Developed, Managed and Implemented 25 different Web applications and tools in 4 years.
- Help to implement SAP ECC 6.0 which consists of 5 modules PP, MM, QM, SD and FI/CO.

Tools used: HTML5, CSS, PHP, MySQL, JavaScript, Windows 10, Sublime 2, Java3D, SAP ECC 6.0.

PHILIPS RESEARCH, The Netherlands — *MSc. Intern Thesis*

JUL 2006 - SEP 2007

 Completed Master's Thesis "CLASSIFICATION OF GESTURES USING POINTING DEVICE BASED ON HIDDEN MARKOV MODEL": A method based on Hidden Markov Models (HMMs) is presented for dynamic gesture trajectory modeling and recognition. Adaboost algorithm is used to detect the user's hand and a contour-based hand tracker is formed combining condensation and partitioned sampling.

Tools used: HMM,HTK, GT^2K , C/C++, Visual Studio 6, UNIX Script, Perl, Matlab 7, LabView 7 and MS Excel.

EDUCATION

Malardalens University, Sweden — Software Engineering, MSc

Jan 2005 - FEB 2007

Independent University, Bangladesh — Computer Science, BSc

AUG 1999 - MAR 2004

Viktorid Berge Gymnasium, Sweden — International Baccalaureate

AUG 1996 - AUG 1997

$\textbf{R\"{o}dabergsskolan}, Sweden-\textit{Upper Secondary Education}$

AUG 1990 - MAR 1996